illustrativemathematics.org 2019-12-03

# Privacy Policy | Illustrative Mathematics

Welcome to Illustrative Mathematics (“we,” “us” or “our”). We are very pleased to have you as a user and member of the community. We know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. This online Privacy Policy is part of Illustrative Mathematics’ Terms of Use, and it applies to our websites, including but not limited to www.illustrativemathematics.org, curriculum.illustrativemathematics.org. It also includes websites that we operate for our partners, such as im.kendallhunt.com.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before accessing the Websites. By using the Websites, you accept and agree to be bound and abide by this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, promptly leave the Websites. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at [privacy@illustrativemathematics.org](mailto:privacy@illustrativemathematics.org).  We’ll be happy to hear your comments and suggestions.

## 1 What does this Privacy Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy explains how Illustrative Mathematics collects and uses information from its users, including our treatment of personally identifiable information. This policy does not apply to websites or practices of companies that Illustrative Mathematics does not own or control.

## 2 What information does Illustrative Mathematics collect?

### 2.1 Information you provide to us

Some of the Websites we operation require users to register. When you register at the Websites, we ask you to provide certain personal information, including but not limited to your name, email address, and organization. When you sign up for our Newsletter, we will ask you for your name and email address in order to contact you in future. We will also collect personally identifiable information from you with your consent when request further information through a contact form on the Website.

### 2.2 Information collected automatically

In order to enable login-based features, we use cookies to store session information for your convenience. A cookie is an identifier that is stored by a browser on the user’s computer. The Website’s cookies do not generate personal data, do not read personal data from your computer, do not store personally identifiable information and are not attached to anything that can be used to identify you. However, you will not be able to log in to the Website if you block or delete cookies.

We collect data from every visitor of the Website to monitor traffic and fix bugs. For example, we collect information such as web requests, the data sent in response to such requests, the Internet Protocol address, the browser type, the browser language, and a timestamp for the request.

### 2.3 What choices do I have?

You are able to view, change and remove your data associated with your profile. Should you choose to delete your account, please contact us at [privacy@illustrativemathematics.org](mailto:privacy@illustrativemathematics.org), and we will honor your request.

## 3 What does Illustrative Mathematics use my information for?

### 3.1 Personal Information

We use your personal information to provide you the Illustrative Mathematics services or products or to communicate with you about the Websites or Illustrative Mathematics services or products.

### 3.2 Usage Information

Illustrative Mathematics may use data to enable us to determine the frequency of users to our Website and its individual pages, so that we can improve and customize our Website and Illustrative Mathematics products

## 4 Does Illustrative Mathematics share my data?

### 4.1 Personal Information

Illustrative Mathematics will not sell your personal information to any third-party organizations for any reason.

### 4.2 Partners

Illustrative Mathematics will sometimes share personal information with other organisations with whom we collaborate with for development and distribution of our products and services. Those partners may send you email correspondence about information and services which they think you may find interesting or helpful, using the email address you have provided. When your personal information is submitted to our partners, they will have no rights to share your personal information with any third parties, and we require them to exercise reasonable care to protect your personal information. You may choose to restrict the use of your personal information by writing to us at [privacy@illustrativemathematics.org](mailto:privacy@illustrativemathematics.org) to request opt-out of communications or restriction on sharing with our partners.

### 4.3 Other required sharing

We do not otherwise share personal information you have provided to us without your consent, unless we have a good faith belief that doing so:

  * is appropriate to carry out your request;
  * is necessary to enforce our Terms of Use;
  * is necessary to detect, prevent or address fraud, security or technical issues;
  * is necessary to otherwise protect our property, legal rights, or that of others; or
  * is required by law or is necessary to comply with the law or legal process or is pertinent to judicial or governmental investigations or proceedings.

### 4.4 Usage Information

Aggregated, anonymized data is periodically transmitted to external services, such as Google Analytics (traffic analysis), Heroku (website hosting), and Amazon Web Services (website hosting and data storage), to help us improve the Website and service. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these third party services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding these third parties’ privacy policies.

Third parties may extract data such as that listed below.

  * Google Analytics: anonymous (ad serving domains, browser type, demographics, language settings, page views, time/date), pseudonymous (IP address)
  * Heroku: hosts some Website applications and user-provided data in a database
  * Amazon Web Services: hosts some Website applications and stores related data

### 4.5 Social Networks

We also use social buttons provided by services like Twitter, Google+, LinkedIn and Facebook. Your use of these third party services is entirely optional. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these third party services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding these third party services’ privacy policies.

### 4.6 Hyperlinks

Information that is available on this Website may include links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of the websites you visit through these links, and you are responsible for reading and understanding these third parties’ privacy policies.

### 4.7 Agents

We employ and contract with people and other entities that perform certain tasks on our behalf and who are under our control (our “Agents”). We may need to share personal information with our Agents in order to provide services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our Agents do not have any right to use personal information or other information we share with them beyond what is necessary to perform their functions. You hereby consent to our sharing of personal information with our Agents.

### 4.8 Business Transfers

If Illustrative Mathematics or some or all of its assets are acquired by or otherwise transferred to another company, or if Illustrative Mathematics goes out of business, or if Illustrative Mathematics changes its tax-exemption status, personal information provided by the user and information concerning the user’s use of the Website may be transferred to or acquired by a third party.

## 5 Is information about me secure?

We intend to protect against unauthorized access of data about you that we store, including personal information. You can help protect against unauthorized access to your account and personal information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately, by limiting access to your computer and browser, and by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Illustrative Mathematics is not liable for unauthorized disclosures of personal information due to no fault of Illustrative Mathematics including, but not limited to, errors in transmission and unauthorized acts of Illustrative Mathematics and/or third parties.

## 6 What if I’m in a different country?

Illustrative Mathematics is operated from the United States. When you use the Website, you are consenting to have your data transferred to and processed in the United States. If you are visiting the Website from outside the U.S., you agree to any processing of any personal information you provide us according to this policy.

## 7 Will Illustrative Mathematics communicate with me?

Illustrative Mathematics may contact you, by email or other means. For example, Illustrative Mathematics may communicate with you about your use of the Illustrative Mathematics website or via our newsletter. We deliberately keep unsolicited communications with users to a minimum.

## 8 Can Illustrative Mathematics change this Privacy Policy?

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. You are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Website after such changes have been first posted, and it is your responsibility to check this agreement periodically for changes. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, the date of the most recent revision will be indicated above and below.

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at [privacy@illustrativemathematics.org](mailto:privacy@illustrativemathematics.org).
